Taking your life from ambition to meaning
The Shift is a documentary, drama film directed by Michael A. Goorjian.
From the creators of You Can Heal Your Life: The Movie comes a compelling portrait
of three modern lives in need of new direction and new meaning.
In his first-ever movie, Wayne Dyer explores the spiritual journey in the second half of life
when we long to find the purpose that is our unique contribution to the world.
The powerful shift from the ego constructs we are taught early in life by parents and society—which promote an emphasis on
achievement and accumulation—are shown in contrast to a life of meaning, focused on serving and giving back.
Filmed on coastal California’s spectacular Monterey Peninsula, The Shift captures every
person’s mid-life longing for a more purposeful, soul-directed life.
Himself (as Dr. Wayne W. Dyer), played by Wayne Dyer.
Denise Moore, played by Portia De Rossi.
Chad Moore, played by Edward Kerr.
David, played by Michael DeLuise.
Joe, played by Ron Marasco.
Quinn Harper, played by Shannon Sturges.
First Shift is a 2024 American crime drama film produced,
written, and directed by the German filmmaker Uwe Boll.
It stars Gino Anthony Pesi as a lone NYPD officer who is forced to team up with a new recruit,
played by Kristen Renton, on his next duty dealing with violent crimes in New York City.
James McMenamin, Willy C.
Carpenter, Brandi Bravo, and Daniel Sauli are featured in supporting roles.
First Shift marks Boll's formal return to filmmaking after eight years on hiatus from the industry, during
which time he set up a now-defunct upscale restaurant in Vancouver and directed a documentary.
Filming on First Shift, which consisted of a non-union crew, began and
completed in March 2023, on location in New York City.
Despite legal hurdles over allegations of unfair labor practices committed on set (which Boll denied), it premiered in his native Germany at the
Independent Days International Filmfest on April 10, 2024, and had a simultaneous release in the United States and Canada on August 30, 2024.
The film explores themes of buddhism, con artist,
enlightenment, consciousness, spiritual journey.
The tone is emotional.